JIN **IGARASHI**

101, Yahata Heights, 2-26-2, Kizuki, Nakahara-ku, Kawasaki city, Kanagawa, Japan · +81 (0)90 9898 6235

igarashi.jin@water-gis.com · www.linkedin.com/in/jinigarashi · https://water-gis.com

Senior software engineer specializing in GIS field with 10 years of work experience in Japan and Eastern Africa. Developed various GIS applications in Fujitsu at the beginning of my career in Japan. Then, worked in Eastern Africa for water supply management by using GIS. Developed GIS systems for assets management of water supply facilities and Non-Revenue Water management and conducted trainings for FOSS4G (Free and Open Source for Geospatial) applications such as QGIS and PostGIS. I am heavily involved in FOSS4G community, now I am mainly translate QGIS/QField application to Japanese language. Also, recently, I joined vector tiles development by United Nation Vector Tile Toolkit, thus I developed my own open source tools which can develop and host vector tiles easily.

EXPERIENCE

JANUARY 2020 - SEPTEMBER 2020

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, ONE COMPATH CO., LTD., JAPAN

Develop and operate the one of most popular web map service in Japan which is called "MAPION". I developed and improved their mapping system which is using Mapbox Vectortiles and Mapserver on Amazon Web Service (AWS).

APRIL 2017 - DECEMBER 2019

CONSULTANT, KOKUSAI KOGYO CO., LTD., JAPAN

Conducted the followings projects funded by Japan International Cooperation Agency (JICA).

- The Project for Strengthening Operation and Maintenance of Rural Water Supply Systems in Rwanda (RWASOM project) (06/2018-12/2019)
- Survey for the Establishment of the Experimental Field for the GNSS System Development in the Kingdom of Thailand (11/2018-11/2019)
- Preparatory Survey for the Project for Strengthening Nzove-Ntora Principal Water Transmission Pipeline in Kigali City, Rwanda" (10/2017-11/2018)

Conducted training workshops for data collection and sharing with FOSS4G applications, then designed & created GIS database and data sharing platform for rural water supply management in RWASOM project. Collaborated with Rwandan colleagues to complete mapping all of water supply systems in the country. The system in Rwanda uses PostGIS, Lizmap/QGIS Server, QGIS Desktop, QField and Garmin GPS.

OCTOBER 2016 – MARCH 2017

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, FUJITSU SOCIAL SCIENCE LABORATORY, LTD., JAPAN

Designed and developed following GIS applications.

• the development of HD map for autonomous vehicle (ArcGIS Server, Python, Django REST framework).

• the system of mapping and simulating location of ships' movement in Singapore (Leafletjs).

APRIL 2014 – SEPTEMBER 2016

GIS SPECIALIST, NAROK WATER AND SEWERAGE SERVICES CO., LTD., KENYA

Worked as a GIS specialist funded by JICA and conducted the following activities.

- Mapped the entire water distribution network (approximately 300km length of pipeline in Total) in Narok and Ololulung'a town (Trimble GPS, ArcPAD, QGIS).
- Designed and developed GIS database & WebGIS (PostGIS, Mapserver, Leafletjs). The system links to billing system, it helps improve their revenue collections.
- Created the DMAs (District Metered Areas) for analyzing and improving Non-Revenue water management.
- Conducted training to transfer technical knowledge to Kenyan colleagues, then GIS system is continuously being used up to now since it has been developed.
- Consulted GIS work for 7 water services providers (Nyeri water, Kabarnet water, Kapsabet water, Nakuru water, Nakuru rural water, Naivasha water and Mavoko water) in Kenya.

APRIL 2009 - MARCH 2014

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, FUJITSU SOCIAL SCIENCE LABORATORY, LTD., JAPAN

Designed and developed the following systems. Most of the systems are related to GIS.

- Web-GIS system for the Real Property Registration system in Ministry of Justice of Japan (Mapserver, OpenLayers, Oracle).
- An Android application for health care management (Java).
- An area marketing system by using MapInfo.
- Logistics and distribution management system with Dijkstra routing algorism (VB.NET, SQL Server, MS Access).

EDUCATION

MARCH 2009

BACHLOR OF ARTS, TOKAI UNIVERSITY, KANAGAWA, JAPAN

Studied history of international relationship between China, Korea and Japan during 16 centuries.

JULY 2007

CHINESE LANGUAGE, SCHOOL OF CHINESE AS A SECOND LANGUAGE, PEKING UNIVERSITY, BEIJING, CHINA

Studied Chinese language and Chinese history for a year.

SKILLS

- Software design and development
- JavaScript (Nodejs, TypeScript, Mapbox GL JS, Leafletjs, OpenLayers, jQuery)
- Python (pandas/geopandas, Django)
- Java
- Database design

- SQL (PostgreSQL/PostGIS, SQL Server, Oracle)
- Training and workshop
- Assets Management
- Non-Revenue Water management
- Data management and analysis

ACTIVITIES

- Developed my own open source tools which can develop and host vector tiles easily for small organization such as water services companies in GitHub (https://github.com/watergis).
- Conducted Japanese translation of QField for QGIS.
- Presented about use cases of Rwanda and Kenya's GIS activities in FOSS4G 2019 Bucharest (https://2019.foss4g.org).
 - O URL of Kenya's presentation: https://media.ccc.de/v/bucharest-135-case-study-of-non-revenue-water-in-kenya
 - O URL of Rwanda's presentation: https://media.ccc.de/v/bucharest-30-case-study-of-data-collection-data-sharing-for-rural-water-supply-management-in-rwanda
- Attended in FOSS4G 2018 Dar es Salaam (https://2018.foss4g.org) in August 2018.
- A member of WaQuAc Net (Water Quality Asian Cooperation Network, http://waquac.net/english)

LANGUAGES

- English (Fluent, IELTS Overall6.0)
- Japanese (Native)
- Chinese (Fluent, HSK Grade 9)
- Swahili (Fluent)